# Nicolas Sesma

nicosesmadev@gmail.com (310) 903-7172

Github: <u>nicosesma</u> Linkedin: <u>nicosesma</u>

### **PROFILE**

A dedicated and versatile web developer experienced working with different technologies to create sustainable systems that are adaptable to changing business requirements. Well versed in Javascript and Node.js, as well as, experienced in using many database systems and online infrastructure platforms to create scalable web applications. Also keen on continuing to learn and implement evolving technologies and paradigms to keep up with the scalability and security concerns involved in creating and maintaining applications.

## Skills Summary

Node.js/Javascript, React/Angular, HTML/CSS, PostgreSQL, MogoDB, GraphQL, AWS, Git, ElasticSearch/Kibana, Translating Business Requirements to Business Specifications

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### VP of Product; Zodaka; Oakland, CA - September 2019 - November 2019

- Helped onboard a new executive CTO and focused primarily on leading the development team and expanding the product roadmap.
- Helped migrate the deployment architecture away from AWS ElasticBeanstalk to a new set of EC2s that ran automatic deployment from a set of AWS CodeBuild/CodeDeploy pipelines.
- Updated tools to be used by system admins to generate processing reports for the auditing and reconciliation of payment processing of certain accounts for banking partners. Began automating the creation and distribution of the banking reports.

### CTO and Co-Founder; Zodaka; Oakland, CA - July 2017 - September 2019

- Technical Cofounder and key member of the group that created and curated the business roadmap and was responsible for leading a development team to meet the goals outlined.
- Created and established the core parts of the system as well as chose the foundational technologies to begin the project for a group of developers to take over.
- Created the architecture of the data models designed to facilitate the processing of payment transactions and management of account information in the system.
- Integrated with various APIs to capture customer financial information and process payments, as well as modularized the system to easily add future integrations.
- Established the criteria for the reconciliation of transactions processed within the system and created tools to facilitate the billing and auditing of service fees used by the accounting departments of the company, merchants and partner banks.

- Researched and implemented new financial tools and networks to grow the business.
- Added analytics to gain further insight of the system usage by clientele for further enhancement of the products and to create better customer service tools.
- Managed the deployment architecture of the system using AWS and ElasticSearch/Kibana.

## Software Engineering Apprentice; Learners Guild - July 2016 - April 2017

- Apprentice software engineer in a program designed to learn the essentials of web
  development by creating multiple projects using Node.js/Javascript, HTML, CSS and
  SQL/NoSQL databases and Git as a software versioning tool.
- Learned how to continue gaining knowledge and experience while working on real time
  projects in a collaborative setting with multiple team members. Helped new program
  members learn and become unblocked with their own projects through pair programming
  and peer code reviews.
- Worked on the real software systems developed and used by the company running the apprenticeship program to create and enhance features for the community of learners and administrators. Worked extensively with the company's software development team while using Node.js, React, and GraphQL.

#### **EDUCATION**

Santa Monica College; Santa Monica, CA — 2011 - June 2013

#### SKILLS OUTLINE

- Programming Languages:
  - Javascript/Node.js
    - React JS / Angular JS (Client Side Rendering Frameworks)
  - Python
- Database Platforms:
  - SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite)
  - NoSQL (MongoDB, Redis, CassandraDB, DynamoDB)
- Deployment Platforms (AWS, Heroku)
- Analytics Frameworks:
  - Google Analytics/ Google Tag Manager
  - Heap
  - Segment
  - Mixpanel
- Blockchain Technology Ethereum/Solidity
- Languages:
  - English Native Fluency
  - French Native Fluency
  - Spanish Native Fluency
  - German Basic Understanding